export const JEWELLERYA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Select the function of jewellery which indicates its economic importance from the list below. It is",
A: "offered as a gift to foster friendship.",
B: "used as a medium of exchange.",
C: "worn to adorn our bodies.",
D: "kept to preserve our culture.",
answer: "B. used as a medium of exchange.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Identify the correct procedure for appreciating a jewellery item from the options below: \nI. perceiving technical qualities. \nII. identifying the work. \nIII. interpreting the work. \nIV. taking inventory of features.",
A: "I, III, II and IV.",
B: "II, III, IV, and I.",
C: "II, IV, I and III",
D: "IV, I, III and II",
answer: "C. II, IV, I and III",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The lustre of a metal shows clearly when it is",
A: "annealed.",
B: "pickled.",
C: "polished.",
D: "soldered.",
answer: "C. polished.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Before drawing a wire to its required size, it must first be",
A: "annealed.",
B: "embossed.",
C: "milled.",
D: "pulled.",
answer: "A. annealed.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The appropriate tool for picking an annealed earring from a charcoal block is",
A: "calipers.",
B: "pliers.",
C: "tong.",
D: "tweezers.",
answer: "D. tweezers.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following pairs of items is classified as costume jewellery?",
A: "Gold and platinum necklaces",
B: "Gold plated pendant and plastic bracelet",
C: "Sapphire and diamond chokers",
D: "Silver brooch and platinum tiara",
answer: "B. Gold plated pendant and plastic bracelet",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A jeweller buffing a copper pendant could be electrocuted due to the material’s",
A: "conductivity.",
B: "ductility.",
C: "fusibility.",
D: "malleability.",
answer: "A. conductivity.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Choose from the options below, a pair of etching materials which act as resist.",
A: "Detergent and wax",
B: "Pumice and asphaltum",
C: "Varnish and pumice",
D: "Wax and asphaltum",
answer: "D. Wax and asphaltum",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. During soldering, the molten solder flows at the",
A: "coldest area.",
B: "cool area.",
C: "hottest area.",
D: "warm area.",
answer: "C. hottest area.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following is the correct procedure for making beads from fine powder? \nI. Ensure that it is compact \nII. Fill the holes with powdered glass \nIII Fix a cassava leaf stalk into each of the holes \nIV. Pack and fire beads in a kiln \nV. Paint the holes of the mould with kaolin \nVI. Add coloured powder to glass powder for aesthetics.",
A: "V, III, II, VI, I, and IV",
B: "V, II, VI, I, IV, and III",
C: "Ill, I, V, IV, II, and VI",
D: "II, VI, V, I, IV, and III",
answer: "A. V, III, II, VI, I, and IV",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. In the traditional setting, a jeweller may be comissioned to produce a dove on a linguist’s staff to be used in",
A: "blessing a marriage.",
B: "inflicting pain on someone.",
C: "promoting war.",
D: "soliciting peace.",
answer: "D. soliciting peace.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The appropriate device for making designs in a molten enamel is",
A: "bodkin.",
B: "pair of tweezers.",
C: "plier.",
D: "scrolling tool.",
answer: "D. scrolling tool.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The main function of a jewellery box is to",
A: "keep the items clean and wearable.",
B: "magnify the items.",
C: "make the items durable.",
D: "protect and preserve the items.",
answer: "D. protect and preserve the items.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. From the options below, identify the melting temperature for aluminium.",
A: "327°c",
B: "660°c",
C: "1083° c",
D: "1539°c",
answer: "B. 660°c",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following processes in the options below is used in joining pieces of copper plates together permanently?",
A: "Chasing",
B: "drawing",
C: "Embossing",
D: "Planishing",
answer: "D. Planishing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Select the most durable organic material from the following options.",
A: "Bamboo",
B: "calabash",
C: "Cane",
D: "Ebony",
answer: "D. Ebony",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. From the options below, identify the alloy that will produce brass.",
A: "Antimony and copper",
B: "Copper and tin",
C: "Copper and zinc",
D: "Magnesium and copper",
answer: "C. Copper and zinc",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following materials is an appropriate binding agent for enamelling?",
A: "Aradite",
B: "Gelatin",
C: "Glue",
D: "Starch",
answer: "A. Aradite",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In perception, which of the following sets of sense organs are linked with weight and rhythm?",
A: "Eye and hand",
B: "Muscle and ear",
C: "Nose and muscle",
D: "Tongue and skin",
answer: "B. Muscle and ear",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. For effectiveness, pickling solution for removing borax flux should be",
A: "cold.",
B: "cool.",
C: "hot.",
D: "warm.",
answer: "C. hot.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Fine silver is alloyed before being used for fabricating jewellery items because it is",
A: "brittle.",
B: "hard.",
C: "rough.",
D: "soft.",
answer: "D. soft.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following decorative techniques is used to hollow-out a design in metal?",
A: "Casting",
B: "Champlevé",
C: "Etching",
D: "Granulation",
answer: "C. Etching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The best protective and finishing material which resists tarnishing of metal jewellery is",
A: "enamel.",
B: "flux.",
C: "pumice powder.",
D: "steel wool.",
answer: "A. enamel.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is a principle for equal attraction on either side of a pendant when threading beads?",
A: "Balance",
B: "Repetition",
C: "Unity",
D: "Variety",
answer: "A. Balance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The most suitable decorative technique for enhancing paper beads is",
A: "burnishing.",
B: "glazing.",
C: "lacquering.",
D: "marbling.",
answer: "C. lacquering.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In multi-purpose soldering, the correct process to use is to begin with",
A: "easy solder, followed by enamelling solder and then hard solder.",
B: "easy solder, followed by soft solder and then hard solder.",
C: "enamelling solder, followed by hard solder then easy solder.",
D: "soft solder, followed by easy solder and then hard solder.",
answer: "B. easy solder, followed by soft solder and then hard solder.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following sets in the options consists of a forming and a cutting tool?",
A: "Centre punch and rolling machine",
B: "Graver and blow torch",
C: "Mandrel and piercing saw",
D: "Rivet and hacksaw",
answer: "C. Mandrel and piercing saw",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which is the most important set of factors to be considered when mounting exhibits for a jewellery exhibition?",
A: "Fixing works on a support, security and visitors book",
B: "Publicity, cost involved and visitors’ book",
C: "Size, weight and height of products",
D: "Type of work, publicity and closing ceremony",
answer: "A. Fixing works on a support, security and visitors book",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The dual functions of a file consists of",
A: "piercing a design and smoothening a surface.",
B: "reducing the cross-section of wire and polishing a surface.",
C: "texturing and polishing a surface.",
D: "Truing up an edge and shaping jewellery items.",
answer: "D. Truing up an edge and shaping jewellery items.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Convert 7.5 lot into 1000 parts.",
A: "333.55/000 Ag",
B: "468.75/000 Ag",
C: "650/000 Ag",
D: "750/000Ag Turn over",
answer: "D. 750/000Ag",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following decorative techniques is used to hollow-out a design in metal?",
A: "Casting",
B: "Champlevé",
C: "Etching",
D: "Granulation",
answer: "C. Etching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The best protective and finishing material which resists tarnishing of metal jewellery is",
A: "enamel.",
B: "flux.",
C: "pumice powder.",
D: "steel wool.",
answer: "A. enamel.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is a principle for equal attraction on either side of a pendant when threading beads?",
A: "Balance",
B: "Repetition",
C: "Unity",
D: "Variety",
answer: "A. Balance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The most suitable decorative technique for enhancing paper beads is",
A: "burnishing.",
B: "glazing.",
C: "lacquering.",
D: "marbling.",
answer: "C. lacquering.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In multi-purpose soldering, the correct process to use is to begin with",
A: "easy solder, followed by enamelling solder and then hard solder.",
B: "easy solder, followed by soft solder and then hard solder.",
C: "enamelling solder, followed by hard solder then easy solder.",
D: "soft solder, followed by easy solder and then hard solder.",
answer: "B. easy solder, followed by soft solder and then hard solder.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following sets in the options consists of a forming and a cutting tool?",
A: "Centre punch and rolling machine",
B: "Graver and blow torch",
C: "Mandrel and piercing saw",
D: "Rivet and hacksaw",
answer: "C. Mandrel and piercing saw",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which is the most important set of factors to be considered when mounting exhibits for a jewellery exhibition?",
A: "Fixing works on a support, security and visitors book",
B: "Publicity, cost involved and visitors’ book",
C: "Size, weight and height of products",
D: "Type of work, publicity and closing ceremony",
answer: "A. Fixing works on a support, security and visitors book",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The dual functions of a file consists of",
A: "piercing a design and smoothening a surface.",
B: "reducing the cross-section of wire and polishing a surface.",
C: "texturing and polishing a surface.",
D: "Truing up an edge and shaping jewellery items.",
answer: "D. Truing up an edge and shaping jewellery items.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Convert 7.5 lot into 1000 parts.",
A: "333.55/000 Ag",
B: "468.75/000 Ag",
C: "650/000 Ag",
D: "750/000Ag Turn over",
answer: "D. 750/000Ag",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The tool which aids proper fusion of a metal joint is",
A: "clip.",
B: "peg.",
C: "pliers.",
D: "wires.",
answer: "D. wires.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Select the softest metal from the options below.",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Gold",
C: "Pewter",
D: "Platinum",
answer: "C. Pewter",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A clay pendant can be made durable by",
A: "applying resin.",
B: "coating with lacquer.",
C: "drying in the sun.",
D: "firing in the kiln.",
answer: "D. firing in the kiln.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Select the best technique for creating a shape from the options below.",
A: "Pickling",
B: "Polishing",
C: "Pounding",
D: "Printing",
answer: "C. Pounding",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Identify the chemical solution for blackening an etched copper sheet from the following:",
A: "ammonium sulphide",
B: "paraffin wax",
C: "nitric acid",
D: "sulphuric acid",
answer: "A. ammonium sulphide",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The decoration technique which involves the use of wire to create small reservoirs from wet is",
A: "champleve.",
B: "cloisonne.",
C: "limoges.",
D: "plique-a-jour.",
answer: "B. cloisonne.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Identify the type of tool in Fig. 1.",
A: "Hand drill",
B: "Ratchet brace",
C: "Strap drill",
D: "Wheel brace",
answer: "B. Ratchet brace",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The main function of the tool in Fig. 1 is to",
A: "bore holes.",
B: "inscribe lines.",
C: "join metals.",
D: "press metals.",
answer: "A. bore holes.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Identify the part labelled i in Fig. 1.",
A: "Chunk",
B: "Crank",
C: "Driving pinion",
D: "Inner pinion",
answer: "C. Driving pinion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following parts indicated in Fig. 1 holds the bit tight?",
A: "i",
B: "ii",
C: "iii",
D: "iv",
answer: "B. ii",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]